Women's Advertising Club of Washington 053
People's Archive, MLK Library
Women's Advertising Club of Washington Records
1943-1975
People's Archive, MLK Library
Women's Advertising Club of Washington
053
1 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed withou series.
Biographical / Historical
Local advertising women organized the Women's Advertising Club of Washington in April 1943 to educate, support, and further the advertising careers of D.C. women. The Club received its charter from the Advertising Federation of America the same year. Initially, members met in each other's homes to share information and educate one another about their work. The club engaged in a number of civic activities during its history, including organizing a speakers bureau in 1946 to provide college lecturers; establishing an annual scholarship award, Publicity Clinic, and a "National High School Essay Contest" in 1951; and sponsoring a biannual political poll luncheon beginning in 1954 with leading politicians and commentators. In 1965 the Club began a public service project, "Widening Horizons," which provided cultural and educational activities for girls in the inner city schools of Shaw and Lincoln Junior High. In 1974 the Club folded its membership into the Advertising Club of Metropolitan Washington with a formal "Agreement of Unification."
Custodial History
Donor unknown.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of board meeting minutes, annual reports, treasurer reports, financial records, clippings, and photographs from the Club's records. It also contains editions of the "Ad Woman of Washington" and "Washington Ad Woman", newsletters of the Club. Of particular significance are photographs, correspondence, memoranda, event programs and other items that document events and activities conducted by the Club in the mid-1960s for inner city girls who named themselves the "Go Girls." The collection also contains short typewritten histories, including a very brief history of the Club (1943-1974). The other histories are all titled "This is Your Life: Women's Advertising Club of Washington, 1943-1953," but are, in fact, the 1953 original and two updated drafts for 1958 and 1967 with annual Club highlights.
Societies and clubs; Women; Organizational Records; Ephemera; Newsletters; Photographs
- Series 1
  - Charter, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs and brochures, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - This is Your Life; Women's Advertising Club of Washington, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Brief [Typewritten] History of WWAC", 1943-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual reports, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Unification correspondence and agreement with Metro, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Closing files/minutes/reports, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (4 folders), 1951-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Ad Woman of Washington, 1951-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Washington Ad Woman, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Washington Ad Woman, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Rosters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Scholarship, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Teen Program, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Treasurers and other financial reports, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Teen Project "Go Girls", 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)